arenaflowers.com 2018-12-27

# Privacy Policy

This privacy notice tells you about the information we collect from you when you use our website www.arenaflowers.com. In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and, by law, we are required to provide you with information about us, about why and how we use your data, and about the rights you have over your data. 

**Who are we?**

We are Arena Flowers (Arena Online Ltd). Our address is Arena Online Ltd, Flowers HQ, Unit 1a, Concord Business Centre, Concord Road, London, W3 0TJ. You can contact us by post at the above address, by email at privacy@arenaflowers.com or by telephone on 0800 0350 581.

We are not required to have a data protection officer, so any enquiries about our use of your personal data should be addressed to the contact details above. 

**How we use your information**

  * When you use our website
  * When you submit an enquiry via our website
  * When you purchase a product from our website
  * When you sign up to receive our newsletter
  * When you download a sample document
  * When you submit a review about us
  * When you take part in our feedback survey
  * Your rights as a data subject
  * Your right to complain
  * Updates to this privacy policy

**When you use our website**

When you use our website to browse our products and services and view the information we make available, a number of cookies are used by us and by third parties to allow the website to function, to collect useful information about visitors and to help to make your user experience better. For more information about our use of cookies, please see our cookie policy. 

**When you submit an enquiry via our website**

When you submit an enquiry via our website, we ask you for your name, contact telephone number and email address.

We use this information to respond to your query, including providing you with any requested information about our products and services. We may also email you several times after your enquiry in order to follow up on your interest and ensure that we have answered your it to your satisfaction. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in providing accurate information prior to a sale.

Your enquiry is stored and processed as an email which is hosted by Google within the European Economic Area (EEA). It is also logged on a CRM system on a cloud server based in Ireland, a country which the EU says has adequate data protection laws in place to protect your data.

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

We keep enquiry emails for two years, after which they are securely archived and kept for seven years, when we delete them. CRM records are kept for three years after the last contact with you. 

**When you purchase a product from our website**

When you purchase products from us online, we ask you for your name, address, contact telephone number, email address and credit card information. We also record your IP (Internet Protocol) address, which is the address of your computer on the Internet.

We will use your information to verify your credit card details for your purchase, process your order and to send you your products. We will also send you a receipt via email and we may use your telephone number to contact you regarding your purchase.

We require this information in order to process your payment, deliver your products or services and fulfil our contract with you. We record your IP address in order to show that the correct tax was applied to the sale, which we are required to do by law.

Your information is stored on our website and on our cloud server, both of which are based within the European Union. Your credit card details are passed to a third-party payment processor which is based worldwide and is certified to PCI compliant. We do not retain your credit card information.

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

We keep your order information for an indefinite period, as the licenses we sell for our products do not expire. 

**When you sign up to receive our newsletter**

When you sign up to receive our newsletter, we ask for your name and your email address.

We will ask for your consent to use your name and email address to email you our newsletter which contains information about our products and other information which we feel might be of interest to you.

You can withdraw your consent at any time and we will stop sending you the newsletter.

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

We keep your personal data for as long as we produce and distribute our newsletter. If you withdraw your consent, we will mark your details so that they are not used and delete them after two years. 

**When you download a sample document**

When you request to download a sample document, such as a white paper, we ask for your name, company name (which is optional) and your email address.

We use this information to email you a link to download the requested document. We may also email you after your download in order to follow up on your interest in our products and services. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in marketing to prospects for our products and services.

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

Your personal data is stored for one year after you requested your download, after which it is deleted. 

**When you submit a review about us**

When you submit a review about us we record your name, your email address and your IP (Internet Protocol) address, which is the address of your computer on the Internet.

We use this information to provide verified independent views about our products and services to potential customers. Your name and the content of your review (but not your email address or IP address) may be publicly displayed on our website. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in marketing our products and services.

Your details are shared with a third party reviews system which is based within the European Economic Area (EEA).

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

Your personal data is stored for as long as we are marketing the product or services that the review refers to, after which it is deleted. You may ask us to remove your review at any time. 

**When you take part in our feedback survey**

When you take part in our feedback survey, we record your name, your email address, your organisation name, your job role and your answers to questions we ask about your opinion of, and use of, our products and services.

We use this information to develop and improve our products and services and our customer relationships. Your job role, organisation and some or all of your comments may be publicly displayed on our website as a testimonial. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in marketing our products and services.

Your details are shared with a third party surveys system which is based within the European Economic Area (EEA).

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

Your personal data is stored for two years, or for as long as we are marketing the product or services that the review refers to, whichever is shorter. You may ask us to remove a testimonial that is based on your feedback from our website at any time. 

**Your rights as a data subject**

By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you, and you can ask us to correct it if it is inaccurate. If we have asked for your consent to process your personal data, you may withdraw that consent at any time.

If we are processing your personal data for reasons of consent or to fulfil a contract, you can ask us to give you a copy of the information in a machine-readable format so that you can transfer it to another provider.

If we are processing your personal data for reasons of consent or legitimate interest, you can request that your data be erased.

You have the right to ask us to stop using your information for a period of time if you believe we are not doing so lawfully.

Finally, in some circumstances you can ask us not to reach decisions affecting you using automated processing or profiling.

To submit a request regarding your personal data by email, post or telephone, please use the contact information provided above in the Who Are We section of this policy.

**Your right to complain**

If you have a complaint about our use of your information, we would prefer you to contact us directly in the first instance so that we can address your complaint. However, you can also contact the Information Commissioner’s Office via their website at www.ico.org.uk/concerns or write to them. 

**Updates to this privacy policy**

We regularly review and, if appropriate, update this privacy policy from time to time, and as our services and use of personal data evolves. If we want to make use of your personal data in a way that we haven’t previously identified, we will contact you to provide information about this and, if necessary, to ask for your consent.

We will update the version number and date of this document each time it is changed. 

### Cookie Policy

We use cookies on this website in a number of ways including the checkout process so the page remembers the product(s) you have chosen. We also use cookies to help tailor your shopping experience to your needs whilst also making your visit to our website more efficient. This is done by collecting certain pieces of personal data about you in a small data file known as a cookie and stored on your computer / internet device. Please note that this is a very common practice with websites and that a cookie cannot harm your computer in any way. The data we store does NOT contain transactional information such as credit card details and is also encrypted.

It is important to understand that you will not be able to order from our website if you do not accept the cookie we place on your computer. To make sure you can accept cookies, you can check your browser settings.

Arena Flowers considers the settings you have selected in your browser as your consent for us to issue you with cookies. If however you decide you do not want to order from us and also want to turn off the ability to accept cookies you can find details on how cookies are enabled on your browser by checking the help catergory of your browser. By doing this you will still be able to browse our website and contact our customer service via email on customer@arenaflowers.com.

For more information regarding cookies and how the affect you please visit this site: [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/)

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements on our behalf. These companies may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is completely anonymous. Your browser can be modified to not accept cookies - guidance for which is provided in the paragraph above. 

Thank you for visiting Arena Flowers.

## The Arena Flowers Team

|    
---|---  
**An experience delivered**  

Back to top
